He's armed... He's adorable... And he's out of school for the entire summer.
Dennis the Menace is a family, comedy film directed by Nick Castle.
Wilson's ever-present annoyance comes in the form of
one mischievous kid named Dennis.
But he'll need Dennis's tricks to uncover a collection of gold coins that go
missing when a shady drifter named Switchblade Sam comes to town.
George Wilson, played by Walter Matthau.
Dennis Mitchell, played by Mason Gamble.
Martha Wilson, played by Joan Plowright.
Switchblade Sam, played by Christopher Lloyd.
Alice Mitchell, played by Lea Thompson.
Henry Mitchell, played by Robert Stanton.
Dennis the Menace (released in the United Kingdom initially as Dennis to avoid confusion with the British comic strip
Dennis the Menace and Gnasher) is a 1993 American comedy film based on the Hank Ketcham comic strip.
It is directed by Nick Castle, written and co-produced by
John Hughes and distributed by Warner Bros.
under its Family Entertainment label.
The plot concerns the misadventures of the mischievous child Dennis Mitchell (Mason Gamble) who menaces his next door neighbor George Wilson (Walter Matthau),
usually hangs out with his friends Joey McDonald (Kellen Hathaway) and Margaret Wade (Amy Sakasitz), and is followed everywhere by his dog Ruff.
Jeannie Russell, who plays Margaret in the 1959–1963
TV series, makes a cameo appearance.
Released in the United States on June 25, 1993, the film was a commercial
success, grossing $117.2 million on a $35 million budget.
Critical reviews were generally negative.
A direct-to-video standalone sequel called Dennis the Menace Strikes
Again was released on July 14, 1998, with a new cast.
A second sequel, A Dennis the Menace Christmas, was
released on November 6, 2007, with a third cast.
The film explores themes of babysitter, based on comic, slingshot.
The tone is lighthearted.